I wonder if it's because
the Crown Princess is expecting,
but she seems much gentler today.
Indeed.
She's usually so reserved
and so aloof.
Yet today, she hasn't stopped smiling.
At a time
of such uncertainty,
His Majesty's health
isn't what it used to be.
We'll keep everything simple.
Today is just a family gathering.
Everyone,
please make yourselves at home.
Prince Lie is on duty today.
Send him
some dishes.
That way,
he can still share
in this family celebration.
Come.
- Thank you, Your Majesty.
- May Your Majesty enjoy everlasting health.
- May you live as long as heaven and earth.
Come.
Please continue chatting, everyone.
I'll go freshen up
and be right back.
Your Highness!
Someone, hurry!
Assassins!
There are assassins!
Someone, hurry!
Protect His Majesty!
Where are the East Palace guards?
Your Highness.
Protect Mother and the ladies first.
Qing, be careful.
Tian Yuan.
Escort the Crown Princess
to the side hall.
Yes.
I'll stay with you.
Don't worry.
Take care of yourself.
Tian Yuan.
Yes.
=Blossoms of Power=
(Adapted from the novel, After My
Bloom, All Flowers Wither by Jin Huang)
=Episode 32=
Quick!
Attack!
Changqing!
Go protect the Grand Empress Dowager!
Your Majesty, your safety comes first.
We should leave now.
Quick, keep up!
Tian Yuan.
Go protect the Crown Prince.
But His Highness told me...
I can protect myself.
Go now.
Yes.
Go.
Although Changtai
is nowhere to be found,
he harbors deep resentment.
He won't let this end so easily.
He's already at the end of his rope.
The Imperial Guard
is heavily guarding the palace.
How could anything still go wrong?
It's because
he's at the end of his rope
that he won't care
about the consequences.
If anything happens in the palace,
I'll have someone send up
a flaming arrow as a signal.
You must bring the troops here at once.
Rest assured, Huayong.
Follow me.
- Yes!
Quick!
Bar the door!
Find something heavy, too.
- Brace the door!
- Yes.
Yes.
Use this.
- This one.
- Over here.
Quick, help me!
- Hurry!
- Here.
This one.
Move!
Put it here.
Okay.
Xihe.
Quick!
Come stand over here.
You're with child.
Don't go any closer.
Mother.
What should we do now?
Judging by what just happened,
I'm afraid there's a traitor among us.
They've colluded with the Palace Guard.
I'm afraid they're staging a rebellion.
What are we going to do?
Stop crying.
The guards are fighting
in the main hall.
They can't spare anyone to rescue us.
There is no back exit here.
There's no way out.
What could
be more frightening than death?
At a time like this,
what do we still have to fear?
What are you doing?
These gold hairpins
are usually just ornaments.
But now,
they can also serve as weapons
to defend ourselves.
Good.
Rather than sit here and wait to die,
we should
fight to the death.
Any daughters of military families
trained in martial arts, step forward.
We'll hold the front.
Everyone else,
fall back to the rear steps.
- Yes.
Zhen Zhu, Mo Yu.
Collect everyone's sachets.
- Yes.
Here.
Your Highness.
Keep these three.
I'm going to prepare an incense blend.
- Yes.
Huayong.
Father.
I trust you've been well.
You ungrateful son!
How could you commit such a heinous act?
Is there
any sense of human decency left in you?
Human decency?
You married me off to a foreign kingdom
and cut off my path to the throne.
Later, after I'd let go of my obsession
and Yanhui and I had fallen in love,
you ordered me
to treat her as an enemy
and forbade me from feeling
the slightest affection for her.
In your eyes,
I was never anything
more than a living sacrifice,
a tool without flesh or blood.
When have you ever
shown me a father's love?
When...
When have you ever truly
loved me as your son?
Shut up!
I,
as the Emperor of Daxing,
must bear the burden of the nation.
Born into the imperial family,
the sovereign
always comes before the father.
You,
care only about
your personal grievances.
When have you ever understood
the burdens of being
an emperor and a father?
Huayong.
Open your eyes.
This is our good father.
All he sees is his throne,
his realm, and his power.
To him, we sons
are nothing more than pawns
to be weighed and sacrificed at will!
Fine.
Father.
Then today,
I will
put an end to all of this!
Huayong.
Now that you know the truth,
why do you still try to stop me?
Changtai.
If you stop now,
there's still a way out.
Even now,
you still believe his lies?
You're beyond saving.
Prince Lie. I am Zhao Zhenghao.
Upon seeing the signal,
I came under the Crown Prince's orders
with Embroidered Envoys
to rescue His Majesty.
Good.
Follow me.
Move!
Quick!
Your Majesty!
Guards!
Watch out!
San Zhi!
Huayong.
Huayong!
Father!
Your Highness!
We can't win this.
Retreat now!
Huayong.
Retreat!
Huayong!
- Your Highness!
- Huayong!
Protect His Majesty!
Yes.
Everyone, follow me!
- Yes.
Changtai.
Stop now.
For the sake of our brotherhood,
I won't kill you.
Go before Father
and confess your crimes yourself.
Changying.
I've always envied you.
Although you were never
Father's favorite son,
you grew up under
your own brother's protection.
No wonder you're so innocent.
I am Father's son, too.
Yet now,
I have become
a traitor everyone in Daxing wants dead.
When did I ever have any brothers?
When...
When did I ever have a father?
I was nothing more than
a living sacrifice,
a bargaining chip
to be weighed and traded.
Yanyan.
I'm coming.
Changtai!
Yanyan.
All your life,
you've always yielded to me.
You've suffered so much.
No matter how reluctant I am,
this time,
I'll do as you wish.
Yanyan.
Changtai.
Farewell.
Huayong.
I'll go find
the Imperial Physician for you.
Rest here in the main hall.
There's no need...
I want to ask you something.
Go ahead.
Who was it,
that poisoned me?
I want to know.
That person...
was it really you?
Huayong.
Over the years,
I've suspected many people,
but I never suspected you.
And more than anything,
I hoped it wasn't you.
So today,
I want to hear it from you.
That person...
who was it?
Was it really you?
Huayong.
It wasn't me.
I didn't poison you.
I never once intended to harm you.
If a single word I say is false,
I'd rather die by your sword.
Huayong.
For more than ten years,
I've searched tirelessly
for the culprit.
Sadly,
there's still no trace of them.
Huayong,
I have failed you.
Huayong.
Father.
I'll never forget
that after I was poisoned,
I was bedridden for months.
Apart from attending court,
you stayed in the East Palace
day and night
to care for me.
You held me in your arms as I lay dying
and knelt at every ancestral shrine.
Your fatherly love
is still vivid in my mind.
If not for your love,
I would never have lived to this day.
If you say you didn't do it,
then I believe you.
Huayong.
My Huayong.
I have failed you.
Grand Empress Dowager,
are you all right?
I'm fine.
Where's the Crown Prince?
He's been in the main hall with Father.
Xihe!
Mother.
Huayong.
What are you doing?
Father.
My condition
is beyond cure.
I beg you, Father,
to grant the child in Xihe's womb
the name Junshu.
Junshu?
This is a name reserved for an emperor.
I...
understand your intention.
You wish to secure a safeguard
for Xihe and your child.
How difficult life will be
for the Crown Princess
of the East Palace without her husband,
and for the young heir
of the East Palace without his father.
My final wish
is that Xihe and our child
may live in peace
and be safe year after year.
I beg you to grant my wish.
Huayong.
I promise you.
Whether it's a boy or a girl,
the child shall be named Junshu.
Thank you, Father, for granting my wish.
Come.
Where are you going?
To find Xihe.
♪Time is like a river flowing backward♪
♪The story is sketched anew♪
♪The moonlight
is sewn together by the dusk♪
♪The tide engulfs the lines on my palm♪
♪Pushing me to converge with you♪
♪Sifting for joy in a sea of sorrow♪
♪I step onto this winding path♪
♪What was swept away?♪
♪Joy and sorrow show no emotion♪
♪The clouds twist into a vortex♪
♪Reaching out to touch you♪
♪Only to find it's just a bubble♪
♪Scene after scene of yesterday♪
♪Lies between the sky and the water♪
♪The stars are sinking♪
♪Like a sunken vow♪
♪You drifted away alone♪
♪Without a single word of goodbye♪
♪Leaving no room to turn back♪
♪I can only stay there forever♪
♪In the coming years, I'll always
remember that year, my graceful lover♪
♪Love hangs on the crest of the waves♪
♪Waiting for regret to swallow me up♪
(Jade Terrace and Auspicious Dew)
Xihe.
It's so good to see you.
Your Highness.
Let me take you
to the Imperial Physician.
Don't go, all right?
I want to talk to you.
I've imagined countless times
what my final moments would be like.
But I never imagined
they would be this beautiful.
The one I love
is right before me.
We're watching the snow together.
It's beautiful.
Xihe.
Do you still remember
the day the maple leaves
were at their reddest?
After our afternoon nap,
we quietly
drank plum juice together.
By the little window,
with the gentle breeze drifting in...
That simple kind of life
was life's greatest blessing.
Your Highness.
We promised
that this year,
we'd watch
the maple leaves together again.
Next year,
we'd count
the apricot blossoms together.
Year after year,
we'd stay by each other's side.
Xihe.
I'm afraid
I have to break that promise.
I barged into your life,
only to leave before you.
I'm sorry.
I only hope
you'll never
regret marrying me...
Marrying you in this life
is something I will
never regret.
♪Let it all go,
give my tears to the flowers♪
♪Beneath my feet, eternal doom
is more than wind and sand♪
♪That perfectly plotted love
hides in the clamor♪
♪Between us, it's both
treacherous and flawless♪
♪I want destiny,
and also tender words of love♪
♪As night stains my eyes, I'll gaze
once more at the rosy clouds♪
♪I have a dream
of a long wind in my sleeves♪
♪My heart rises and falls,
we embrace in a sea of clouds♪
♪In this eternity, you are a part of it♪
♪My longing can level mountains
and cross countless rivers♪
♪Drunk or sober, it's all like a dream♪
♪Stars sink into my hair,
the moon slips through my fingers♪
♪For how much joy
do we share this life together♪
♪Withering and flourishing,
year after year♪
♪I have a dream
of a long wind in my sleeves♪
♪My heart rises and falls,
we embrace in a sea of clouds♪
♪In this eternity, you are a part of it♪
♪My longing can level mountains
and cross countless rivers♪
♪Drunk or sober, it's all like a dream♪
♪Stars sink into my hair,
the moon slips through my fingers♪
♪For how much joy
do we share this life together♪
♪Withering and flourishing,
year after year♪
♪May the sand and dirt in my sleeves♪
♪Become the tears
in the corner of my eyes♪
♪And blossom into a flower♪
What he could do,
I can do as well.
From beginning to end,
I have always been your husband.
Why was it Xiao Huayong,
and not me?
In this world,
no one can compare to him.
If even the gods refuse to save me,
then I'll save myself.
Shen Xihe.
She will become my consort.
♪I've hidden so many words♪
♪Too reluctant to tell you♪
♪So never uncover♪
♪The sand that slips away
with one grasp♪
♪The flower that withers
after one bloom♪
♪Silently buried deep inside my heart♪
♪Every answer I gave♪
♪Was both bittersweet and absurd♪
♪Hiding my tear-filled eyes
when I hurt you♪
♪How hard it truly was?♪
♪The wounds that healed
with just a little comfort♪
♪The lies made whole
with a single embrace♪
♪Pretending to be brave
as if I'd never been hurt♪
♪It's a shame I never could♪
♪Give you a moon in return♪
♪With the same open heart you loved me♪
♪I've crossed the wasteland of memories♪
♪Never knowing I was lost♪
♪Why don't you take me away?♪
♪Lead me out of this endless game
of hide-and-seek♪
♪You'll never♪
♪Know how much I long to, long to♪
(No animals were harmed
in the making of this film)